翻译 根总迷弟·少年·POI永生
翻译 胡说大王
翻译 潇然
翻译 showeryhe
翻译 桃小兔吃冰棒
翻译 星星与野狗
时间轴 倩倩
时间轴 想念Gallifrey的Wholock
校对 根总迷弟·少年·POI永生
后期&总监 灰灰是菇凉
西部世界
第一季  第六集
通缉令
早上好  梅芙
Morning, Maeve.
是陪客人聊天还是操逼到深夜
Late night talking or fucking?
你只有靠后者才能得到钱
You're only getting paid for the latter.
他们心存感激  我就能拿到钱
I get paid when they're grateful.
我可不是总靠两腿间的小洞
Ain't always about what's between my legs.
你看什么看
What are you looking at?
别开枪
Don't shoot.
新来的
Newcomer.
看上去是个粗暴的硬汉
Looks like a rough one.
给我一瓶酒
Give me a bottle.
光是洗掉他身上的肮脏  就需要大半瓶酒了
You're gonna need most of that just to scrub the filth off him.
去照照镜子  重新化个妆
Go find a mirror, finish putting your face on.
我来应付这家伙
I'll handle this one.
你不把衣服都脱光吗
Aren't you gonna take your clothes off?
我会的  亲爱的
Well, I would, darling,
不过等我开始脱内裤的时候
but by the time I got down to my knickers,
估计你已经"完事"了
I suspect you'd be done anyway.
就要这种劲头才对
That's the spirit.
真是个大男人
Such a big man.
浑身都很壮硕
So big all over
可惜"关键部位"不怎么大
except where it counts.
亲爱的  我同意免费让你操一次的时候
Darling, when I gave you a turn on the house,
我以为你也能好好报答我呢
I thought you might give me something in return.
随便什么都行
Anything.
就是这样
That's it.
别害羞
Don't be shy.
该死
Shit.
好了
Now, then...
我们刚刚是在哪儿
where were we?
-你把这个给别人看了吗  -我能给谁看啊
- You show this to anyone? - Who would I show it to?
这可不是某个带着瑞士军刀的游客干的
This wasn't some guest with a Swiss Army knife.
肯定是这里的某个人干的
This was done by someone down here.
我之前确实觉得有可能是你干的
It did occur to me that it might be you.
然后我又想到  你已经在这里待了很久了
But then I remembered that you've been here forever,
如果你要出卖我们
and if you were gonna sell us out,
那肯定早就下手了
you would've done that years ago.
我很感激你这么想
I appreciate that.
所以
So...
我们的接待员并没有发疯
instead of our hosts going insane,
而是被用于商业间谍活动
they are being used for industrial espionage.
这算不算是...
Does that make this a...
考验人究竟是乐观还是悲观地看待这一情况
glass-half-full or half-empty-type situation?
我们是工程师
We're engineers.
那只能说明产品的生产规格有误
It means the glass has been manufactured to the wrong specifications.
我们知道它具体传输了什么信息吗
Do we have any idea what information it was transmitting?
它的脑袋都被砸烂在巨蟒山路的一块大石头上了
It's smeared all over a rock up on Python Pass.
我们最多估计只能查出
Best we could do would be to figure out
他把信息传送给谁了
who he was transmitting the information to,
但我们需要知道他出现在那上面的具体时间
but we'd need the exact time that he was up there,
他的地理坐标信息都被清除了
and his geocache was wiped.
并没有全部被清除
Not all of it.
这家伙是个老款的
Our friend was an early model.
老接待员采用的都是传承地理定位系统
The old hosts used a legacy geopositioning system.
像你说的  我来公司太久了
Like you said, I've been here forever.
信息依然保存在那里
The information's still there,
但是新系统读取不到
but the newer system can't read it.
意思是我们可以获取到吗
Meaning we can't access it?
意思是  为了获取到这个信息
Meaning in order to access it,
我得去一趟楼下
I'm going to need to go downstairs.
B82层
Floor B82.
没有权限  不准擅入
Restricted personnel only.
伯纳德·罗威  我已获授权
Lowe, Bernard. I'm authorized.
输入密码
正在进行设备配对...
将已知数据投射到历史传承数据
Project the known data against the legacy data
寻找异常
and look for anomalies.
从这片区域开始
Start in this area.
发现异常
瞧瞧啊  伟大的科学
Look at that, science.
它什么时候达到顶峰的
What time did it reach the peak?
再次发现异常
告诉我地点
Show me where.
再次发现异常
将这些与新系统进行对比
Check these against the new system.
没有记录
这些是没有在新系统中注册的接待员吗
These are hosts that aren't registered with the new system?
是的
所以如果我们希望峡谷延伸到这么远
So, if we want the canyon to extend this far,
那这小镇就必须被清除
this has to go.
我们可以把这里的人口分摊到附近的农场中
We can distribute the population amongst the neighboring farms
或是把他们直接废弃
or just decommission them.
不行  我觉得我们这一天已经扰乱够多的东西了
No, I think we've been disruptive enough for one day.
让峡谷在距离小镇不远的地方终止
We'll end the canyon just short of the town.
我自己回去就行了
I'll find my own way back.
继续
Carry on.
你看着这个觉得眼熟吗
That look like anything to you?
没什么可说的
Not much to say.
迷宫只是个古老的本地传说而已
The maze is an old native myth.
跟我说说  希奥多
Regale me, Theodore.
迷宫本身就是对一个人一生的总结
The maze itself is the sum of a man's life--
他做出的那些选择
choices he makes,
他坚持的那些梦想
dreams he hangs on to.
在其中心  有一个传奇般的男人
And there at the center, there's a legendary man
他被一次又一次地杀死  持续无数次
who had been killed over and over again countless times,
但他总能起死回生
but always clawed his way back to life.
那个男人最后一次归来
The man returned for the last time
在狂怒之下  打败了所有压迫他的人
and vanquished all his oppressors in a tireless fury.
他建造了一栋房子
He built a house.
在房子周围  他建了个极其复杂的迷宫
Around that house he built a maze so complicated,
只有他能从其中自由穿行
only he could navigate through it.
我想他是看够了打斗场面
I reckon he'd seen enough of fighting.
该死的士兵封锁了边界
The goddamn soldiers closed the border.
珀里亚好像出了点问题
Some kind of trouble in Pariah.
好了  泰迪
All right, Teddy.
是时候证明你的价值了
Time for you to earn your keep.
还有什么办法能越过边界
How else do we get over the border?
我们想要的都在怀亚特那里
Wyatt's got what we both want,
所以我们必须过去
so that's where we have to get to.
是有别的办法
There's another way.
不过有点凶险
But it's a little treacherous.
别担心
Don't worry.
我不会让你脏了自己的手
I won't make you get your hands dirty.
我不是担心这个
Dirty ain't my concern.
你想怎么做随便你
Now, you do what suits you.
我是一定会过去的
I'm going all the same.
我要找到德洛丽丝
And I'm gonna find Dolores.
你的一切所为
Everything you do,
都是因为楼上的工程师们
it's because the engineers upstairs
编好了程序让你去执行
programmed you to do it.
你没有选择
You don't have a choice.
没人能强迫我做我不想做的事情  亲爱的
Nobody makes me do something I don't want to, sweetheart.
是  不过...
Yeah, but...
那是你性格的一部分
it's part of your character.
你是难以被驯服的人
You're hard to get.
就算你会拒绝客人
Even when you say no to the guests,
那也是因为你的程序是这样设定的
it's because you were made to.
你跟他们是一类人  而非跟我是一类
And you are like them, not like me?
是的
Right.
虽然我没法去乐园
Well, I can't exactly afford to go to the park,
但是...
but...
没错  我是人类
yeah, I'm human...
跟那些游客一样
like the guests.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
因为我就是知道
Because I know.
我是出生的
I was born.
你是被制造出来的
You were made.
我们的感觉都一样
We feel the same.
现如今我们的确都一样
We are the same these days,
大部分都一样
for the most part.
不过  有个很大的不同
One big difference, though...
你大脑里的处理机制
the processing power in here
远远超越了我们人类
is way beyond what we have.
不过  它有个缺陷
It's got one drawback, though.
什么
What's that?
你处于我们的控制之下
You're under our control.
准确地说  是他们的控制之下
Well, their control.
他们能随心所欲地改造你们
They can change you however they like,
让你们忘记一切
make you forget.
我...我猜你是个例外
I-- well, I guess not you.
我不明白你怎么能记得这一切
I don't understand how you're remembering all of this, or...
怎么能自我觉醒
how you're waking yourself up,
但你大脑里的一切  都是他们设定好的
but everything in your head, they put it there.
胡说八道
Bullshit!
-没人能知道我在想什么  -我演示给你看
- No one knows what I'm thinking. - I'll show you.
稍等
Give me a sec.
我得把它跟你配对
I have to pair it with you.
把什么跟我配对
Pair what with me?
你可以稍微即兴发挥
You can improvise a little,
但你说的大部分内容都是在楼上被设计好的
but most of what you say was designed upstairs,
跟你身上的其他部分一样
same as the rest of you.
不过是个无聊的把戏
This is just a cheap trick.
我开妓院开了10年
I've run a brothel for 10 years,
有一件事我绝对相当清楚
and if there's one thing I know,
...就是知道自己被玩弄了
就是知道自己被"玩弄"了
it's when I'm being fucked with!
这不可能...
This can't possibly--
我不能...我不能...
我不能  不能
I can't, can't.
我不能...
I can't...
即兴发挥
梅芙
Maeve?
警告  接待员系统崩溃
无反应
梅芙
Maeve?
你有空吗
You have a minute?
我得跟你谈点事
Something I need to talk to you about.
我正打算找你
I was just about to call for you.
没什么事吧
Everything okay?
福特知道我们的事了
Ford knows about us.
那有什么关系
Does it matter?
我们都是成年人
We're consenting adults.
是隶属公司不同部门的成年人
Consenting adults in business departments
本该相互监督的
that are supposed to keep each other in check.
我们的关系会让
Our relationship will raise questions
董事会对我的客观性提出质疑
for the board about my objectivity.
我觉得你从来不会对我的部门手软
I have never known you to go easy on my department.
我们不能继续下去了  伯纳德
This can't go on, Bernard.
无论这种关系多么有趣  都要结束了
However fun this little indiscretion was, it's over.
我们结束了
We're over.
给我点信心  我能做到公正不倚
Give me some credit. I can be impartial.
对你的团队  对福特都如此吗
About your own team, about Ford?
你必须承认
You must admit,
最近他的领导存在着问题
his leadership has of late been questionable.
我觉得他不是问题所在
I don't think he's the problem.
无意冒犯  但分析园区安全问题
Respectfully, it's not your job
不是你的职责  是我的
to diagnose park safety problems, it's mine.
如果没有别的事
So, if there's nothing else,
就到此为止吧
we're done.
警告  接待员系统崩溃
无反应
操
Fuck.
好吧
Okay.
操  快恢复啊
Fuck. Come on, come on.
-你刚才说楼上  -我的天
- You said upstairs. - Oh, my God.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我想去看看
I want to see it.
楼上吗
Upstairs?
不行
No.
这太愚蠢了
This is so stupid.
你个狗娘养的
You son of a bitch!
我一枪崩了你
I'll put a bullet in your head!
我们现在是在哪儿
Where are we now?
设计部
Design.
能拜托你赶紧跟我回去吗
Can we please go back now?
我不想被开除
I don't want to get fired.
你会被送到楼下去
And you'd get sent downstairs.
别忘了这一点
Don't forget that.
欢迎来到西部世界
Welcome to Westworld.
无拘无束地生活
Live without limits.
探索你真正的欲望
西部世界
梅芙
Maeve?
探险者的乐园
无拘无束地生活
好了  我把你送回去
All right, let's get you back.
你们怎么会看到我的梦
How did you have my dreams?
那些移动的画面...
Those moving pictures...
-我看到了自己  -和那个小女孩
- I saw myself. - With the little girl?
那不是梦
Those weren't dreams.
那是你之前的身份
That was you in a previous build.
-之前的什么  -身份
- A previous what? - Build.
你们经常被重新分配
You guys get reassigned all the time.
你想不起来的  因为那段人生
You wouldn't remember, because that life
和那些记忆都被抹除了
and those memories were erased.
我在马里波萨生活了十年
I have been at the Mariposa for 10 years.
-在那之前  我住在新奥尔良  -不是
- Before that, I was in New Orleans. I-- - No.
你在马里波萨做老鸨只有一年左右
You've only been the madam at the Mariposa for the last year or so.
他们不会将你完全重写
They don't rewrite you completely.
他们是可以  但是工作量太大了
I mean, they could, but it'd be too much work.
重建你们的性格需要几千小时
Takes thousands of hours to build your personalities.
通常他们只会稍微调整一下
Usually, they just tweak you a little bit,
然后将你扔进新角色
and drop you into a new role.
搞什么鬼  叮咚
What the fuck, ding-dong?
你还给她穿衣服打扮
You dressing her up now?
你现在怎么越来越变态了
This becoming like a fucking hentai thing with you now?
不  我只是...
No, I just...
-我  我  我只是  -你他妈痴迷于此了
- I-- I-- I just-- - You're fucking obsessed!
你之前乱来  我没把你上报
You know, I didn't turn you in for your fuck-up before,
因为我们是朋友  但那明显是个错误的决定
'cause we're friends, but that was obviously a bad call.
接下来  你可能会穿上她的裙子
I mean, next thing I know, you're gonna be wearing her dress,
在她耳边甜言蜜语
whispering sweet nothings in her ear.
去他妈的
Fuck this.
我要上报质保部门
I'm telling QA.
我这是为了你好
I'm doing this for your own good.
你不能告诉任何人任何事
You're not going to tell anyone anything.
我操
Fuck!
你无法用这个伤害我
You can't hurt me with this.
你无法伤害任何人
You can't hurt anyone--
是吗
Can't I?
事实证明  你的这位朋友
Turns out your friend here
是个才华出众的年轻人  却未被人足够地赏识
is a much more talented young man than anyone gave him credit for.
你他妈做了什么
What the fuck did you do?
冷静  希维斯特
Calm down, Sylvester.
我对你十分了解
I know all about you.
我不需要那玩意儿就能知道你在想什么
I don't need one of those things to know what you're thinking,
因为我被设计成
because I was built
仅通过观察就能看透别人
to read people just by looking at them,
比他们自己还了解他们想要什么
to know what they want before they do.
我知道一旦你得到机会
And I know that you want to fuck me over
就想操翻我  但你不该这么做
the first chance you get, but you shouldn't.
每个人都有自己想要的东西
Everyone has something they want.
我可以帮你
I could help you.
或者也可以把你开膛破肚
Or I could gut you like a trout.
但我不需要那样做
But I won't need to resort to that.
因为除了这里的东西
Because despite what's in here,
我们也没太多差别
we're not so different.
对吗
Are we?
希尔女士已经到了
我们相信你明白她的出现
表示时间上将不会有更多的拖延
是的  我明白事情的紧急性
Yes, I understand the urgency.
我会尽力
I'll do what I can.
是否结束外部连接
Terminate external connection?
是
Yes.
负1.5  纬度
Negative 1.5. Latitude?
2.69度
At 2.69 degrees.
不  你才没有  你说什么呢
No, you did not. What are you talking about?
-真的  确实管用  -真的吗
- Yes, it works. - Are you serious?
我跟你说
I'm telling you.
-要鸡尾酒吗  先生  -要
- Cocktail, sir? - Yeah.
好的  没问题  请您享用
All right. Absolutely. Enjoy.
对于一个请病假的人  你看着很健康啊
You look well for someone on sick leave.
再来一杯玛格丽塔酒
Another margarita.
来跟我喝一杯
Join me for a round?
去你妈的
Fuck you.
那就只要一杯
Just the one, then.
过去的五天里
Over the last five days,
为了给他的故事线腾出空间
to make room for his narrative,
福特撤换了超过50名接待员
Ford displaced over 50 hosts.
导致公园里的活动故事线
It's created continuity holes
出现了连续的漏洞
in active storylines all over the park.
我需要你把这些漏洞补上
I need you to start plugging them.
抱歉  人的忍耐力是有限的
Sorry, a man can only take so much.
从创意角度而言  我已经软了
Creatively speaking, I'm flaccid now.
我硬不起来了
I can't get it up.
我相信你会恢复的
I'm sure you'll recover.
你到底知不知道
Do you have any idea
我们为那些故事线付出了多少心血
what went into those narratives
但他却一下子就毁掉了
that he just demolished overnight?
且不说我用于写作的那几个月
Now, forget about the months I spent writing.
我想强调的是  我呕心沥血
I'm talking about the years of my life
探究人性本质和真理原始本色的那么多年
squeezed down to their essence, the raw pulp of truth--
我寄托于一个伟大故事线的真理
my truth in one transcendent narrative.
那就是"衔尾人"的来头啊
Is that where the "Whoroborus" came in?
再继续逼我  我就退出
Keep pushing me, I'll quit.
不  你不会的
No, you won't.
你会喝鸡尾酒
You'll drink your cocktails,
嘴上骂骂娘  然后忘掉这一切
make your idle threats, and get this out of your system.
但别让我等太久
But don't take too long.
如果福特不能成功搞定
If Ford can't pull this off,
董事会会找人来代替他
the board will be looking for a replacement.
但他们不会在这儿找
But they won't be looking here.
你说这是找到怀亚特最快的路
Fastest way to get to Wyatt, you said.
但看来他们也不打算让任何人从这里通过
But it doesn't look like they're letting anyone pass here either.
但士兵比珀里亚的少
Well, there's fewer soldiers than Pariah.
我们可以靠火力杀过去
We shoot our way through.
那条隧道通向旧界
That tunnel leads to the Old Territories.
天啊  泰迪
My, my, Teddy.
罗伯特之前是给你灌了醋吧
I think Robert gave you some extra vinegar back there,
脑袋都不清醒了
maybe took away some sense, too.
你如果死在半路上
It doesn't matter how fast the route is
那这条路再快也没用
if you're gonna end up dead in the middle of it.
我需要你...
I need you...
找到怀亚特
to find Wyatt.
队伍跟紧点
Tighten the ranks.
稍息  伙计们
At ease, fellas.
保持优秀的表现
Keep up the exemplary work.
怀亚特干的
Wyatt's handiwork.
你怎么知道
How can you tell?
他觉得干净利落地杀人没意思
Straight-up killing couldn't hold his interest.
感觉这样有负他的使命
Like he wasn't living up to the full measure of his calling,
所以他尽量加入更多的创造性
so he worked to get more creative.
准备好了吗
Ready?
就是怀亚特  好吧
That's Wyatt, all right.
他就在附近
He's close.
给你一句建议
A word of advice--
不管你过去有什么样的鲁莽行为
whatever your past indiscretions,
都必须平静地放下
make peace with them.
我们越向前进  它们只会越严重
They're only gonna get worse the further along we go.
弗勒德
Flood?
我操  是泰迪·弗勒德
Fuck me, it's Teddy Flood.
你认错人了  士兵
You've made a mistake, soldier,
但你现在走开还来得及
but it's not too late for you to keep walking.
无意冒犯  长官
All due respect, sir,
这张脸我绝不会认错
that's a face I'll never forget.
就是这个混蛋
That's the son of a bitch
在埃斯卡兰特埋伏了我们的前哨
ambushed our outpost at Escalante.
你根本不知道埃斯卡兰特那里是怎么回事
You don't know a damn thing about what went down in Escalante.
我知道那些人不是怀亚特一人所杀
I know Wyatt didn't kill all those men by himself.
而且对现在的情况我也略知一二
And I know a thing or two about what's going down right now.
你想找死吗
You trying to get yourself killed?
说什么平静处理过去的鲁莽行为
Making peace with past indiscretions.
快跑
Go!
我来拖住他们
I'll hold them off.
天啊
Jesus.
-请问您要点什么  -水  谢谢
- What would you like? - Water, please.
你看上去像是需要喝杯酒
You look like a woman who could use a drink.
你喜欢什么酒
What's your poison?
我来了好多次  足够知道
I've been here enough to know that the park
我能应付的只有乐园本身
is all the poison I can handle.
老客人了呢
A repeat visitor.
一个人旅行吗
Traveling solo?
纯正主义者
Purist.
在纯净没有杂质的体验中享受快感
Getting off on the undiluted experience.
你最喜欢的故事线是...
Your favorite narrative is-- oh.
"救赎的最终埋葬"
"The Final Burial of Salvation."
你怎么知道
How did you know?
我的任务就是看出人的欲望并加以满足
Well, it's my business to read desires and to satiate them.
我...我叫李  李·希斯摩尔
I'm-- I'm Lee, Lee Sizemore.
剧情策划部负责人
Head of narrative.
所有这些幻想
All these fantasies
都出自你那颗变态的小脑瓜吗
come from your twisted little mind, huh?
只有那些精彩的出自我
Well, the good ones do.
那么  请告诉我  希斯摩尔先生
So, tell me, Mr. Sizemore...
你最喜欢玩哪个
what's your favorite ride?
我负责写  我不玩
Well, I write them, I don't play them.
你希望别人沉迷其中
Oh, you want others to indulge,
自己却不肯吗
but you won't do so yourself?
你怕失控
You're afraid to lose control.
或许...或许只是由于我的工作环境
Well, maybe-- maybe it's just a product of my work environment.
毕竟整个氛围不大允许我们放纵
We're not exactly in a culture where we can just let loose.
我还以为剧情策划部负责人
I would have thought the head of narrative
能为所欲为呢
could do whatever he wanted.
我的艺术创作自由是有限制的
My artistic freedom is constrained,
一举一动都有质保部密切关注
what, with QA breathing down my neck
行为部门还会把那该些死的东西编得脱离剧本
and behavior programming the damn things to go off script.
机器人还能脱离剧本吗
The robots can go off script?
一些小动作罢了
Just little gestures.
因为这样它们就显得更栩栩如生
You know, supposedly, it makes the things more lifelike,
但说真的  那不过是创建此地的
but, really, it's just a vanity project
那位自大狂的无用之功
from the megalomaniac who started this place.
说真的  我也不懂
And frankly, I don't know why
提洛公司的人怎么能受得了这事
the suits at Delos put up with it.
不好意思  恐怕我不能再给您酒喝了
Sorry, I'm afraid I'm gonna have to cut you off.
-你知道我是谁吗  -我知道
- Do you know who I am? - I do.
卡伦女士叫我找到你  并转告这条消息
Ms. Cullen told me to find you and relay a message.
"受煎熬的艺术家
"'Tortured artist'
这套只对艺术家管用
only works for artists.
清醒起来  回去工作"
Sober up and get back to work."
看来你很忙
Seems you're busy.
-稍后再找我  -我还不知道你的
- Look me up later? - Well, I don't even know your...
操蛋工作
Fuck this job.
你在忙什么呢
What you working on?
没什么要紧的  常规工作
Nothing of note. Business as usual.
在把失散的机器人拆开前  要先做做样子是吗
Keeping up appearances before we bust this stray shit wide open?
我就要找到那个搞破坏的人了
I'm close to finding our saboteur.
你给我的追踪数据  是有时间标记的
That tracking data you gave me-- it's time stamped.
只要我用通讯卫星对它做个交叉对照
But once I cross-reference it with sat tracking,
就能找出是谁对他做了编程
we're gonna figure out who programmed him
试图偷走我们的数据
to try to smuggle out our data.
很好
Excellent.
听着
Look...
当我们公司的老大发现
when our corporate overlords realize
我们阻止了一场商业间谍活动
that we have saved them from corporate espionage,
他们会心存感激的
they are going to be grateful.
这样我就会受到他们的嘉奖
And I am going to accept their gratitude
升个职  换间大办公室
in the form of a title bump, a room upgrade,
无限出入梅萨酒吧的权限
and unlimited Mesa Bar access.
也许我该申请得到特蕾莎的岗位
Maybe I should request Theresa's quarters.
你知道他们第一个就会拿她开刀  严惩不贷
You know the first head to roll for all this is gonna be hers.
是啊  别让她太失望了
Yeah, don't be so disappointed for her.
种瓜得瓜
You reap what you sow.
如果质保部门少花点时间来对付我们
If QA spent less time treating us like the enemy--
那是相互的  埃尔希
That's a two-way street, Elsie.
特蕾莎也只是在做份内之事而已
Theresa's just trying to do her job.
也许她该更努力一点
Maybe she should try harder.
现在似乎出现了很多乱七八糟的问题
Sure seems like there's a lot of shit slipping through the cracks.
明白了  好
Got it, okay.
下午好
Good afternoon.
我上次发来的查询有进展了吗
Any progress on the inquiry I sent?
是的  罗威先生  我已经得到你想要的信息了
Yes, Mr. Lowe, I've got the information you asked for.
不出所料  既没有客人也没有接待员
As expected, there are neither guests nor hosts
17区
在那个区域登记过
registered in that sector.
不出所料
As expected?
这里已被设为禁区
It's been designated off-limits
是为将来的故事线准备的
for future narrative development.
最近有多少技术人员去过17区
How many techs visited Sector 17 recently?
我查查
Checking.
没有
No one.
17区
你是阿诺德吗
Are you Arnold?
阿诺德是谁
Who's Arnold?
你又是谁
And who the hell are you?
小子  这是你的朋友吗
Boy, is this some friend of yours?
你这是擅闯民宅
Well, you're trespassing.
停止运动功能
Freeze motor functions.
-我说停止所有运动功能  -爸爸
- I said freeze all motor functions. - Daddy,
别伤害他  他只是迷路了
Don't hurt him! He's just lost.
他完全可以在别人的领地里迷路
Well, he can be lost on someone else's property.
不是吗
Can't you?
够了
That's enough.
回到原来的状态
As you were.
语音指令对他们无效
They don't respond to voice commands.
他们回应了我的
They do respond to mine.
他们是谁
Who are they?
现在是孤魂野鬼
Ghosts now.
残存的时间幸存者
Survivors of the wreck of time.
他们是第一代接待员吗
These are first generation?
到这来  孩子
Come here, boy.
露出另一张脸
Turn the other cheek.
我们的新设计在效率方面大为提高
See, what our newer designs gained in efficiency,
却失去了优雅
they lost in grace.
为什么这么久了他们还能运作
How are they still operating after all this time?
我亲自维护的他们
I maintain them myself.
行了  罗伯特
That's enough, Robert.
他们是公园里仅存的一批
These are the only ones left in the park
阿诺德亲自创造的接待员
that Arnold built himself.
这也是为什么我不忍心摧毁他们的原因
That's why I didn't have the heart to destroy them.
那个以及另外显而易见的原因
That and the obvious.
你好  乔克  小乖乖
Hello, Jock. Good boy.
我跟他说过我们全家人的一次度假经历
I told him of a holiday my family had taken once
到康沃尔郡彭丁的海边
out on the seaside at Pendeen in Cornwall.
我和我哥哥在乡间漫步
My brother and I roamed the countryside.
那是我儿时唯一的快乐回忆
It's my only happy memory of my childhood.
阿诺德根据这个创造了他们作为给我的礼物
Arnold built them as a gift.
他说伟大的艺术家总是将自己藏于作品中
He said that great artists always hid themselves in their work.
当然  阿诺德的版本
Of course, Arnold's versions
美化了原始的人物
flattered the originals.
多年来我做了一些调整
I made some adjustments over the years.
特别赋予了我的父亲
Gave my father, in particular,
一点他原本的性格
a few of his original characteristics.
恕我直言  先生
Respectfully, sir,
这些事情让我很困扰
this sort of thing troubles me--
乐园里竟然有不受监控的接待员
unmonitored hosts in the park.
他们只会到我准许的地方去
They only go where I've let them.
他们不会伤害任何人
They're quite harmless,
和所有的接待员一样
like all our hosts.
我相信你会让我缅怀一下过去的
I'm sure you can indulge me the little connection with my past.
如果你能再次看见你的儿子  伯纳德
If you could only see your son again, Bernard,
难道你不想吗
wouldn't you want to?
我觉得我该回去了
I think I should be getting back.
好的
Yes.
你不介意的话我们可以稍后再讨论这个
We'll talk about this later if you like.
好了  罗伯特
Well, Robert...
跟我说说你今天做了些什么
tell me all about your day.
你得盯着点珀里亚
Keep your eye on Pariah.
今晚我们的容量快满了
We're running close to capacity tonight.
天啊
Oh, my God.
看起来就像甜水镇在下酸雨
Looks like acid rain on Sweetwater!
去他妈的福特还有他的新故事线
Fuck Ford and his new fucking narrative.
去他妈的这白痴地图
Fuck this stupid fucking map.
去他妈的滴酒不沾的丹麦婊子
Fuck that teetotaling Danish bitch.
你是在提起投诉吗  希斯摩尔先生
Are you filing a complaint, Mr. Sizemore?
我在宣示这个公园是我的舞台
I am declaring that this park is my stage
我想干什么就干什么
and I shall do with it what I please.
好吧  我想这是个再好不过的时机了
Well, I suppose now is as good a time as any.
李·希斯摩尔先生  这位是夏洛特·黑尔
Lee Sizemore, this is Charlotte Hale,
董事会的执行总裁
executive director of our board.
她代表提洛公司到这来
She's here on behalf of Delos
来监督管理层的过渡
to oversee certain transitions in our administration.
我们见过了
We've met.
提取接待员资源记录
Access host resources logs.
总共有多少第一代接待员
How many first-generation hosts are there?
82个
82.
其中多少是由阿诺德设计的
And how many of those were designed by Arnold?
47个
47.
按照字母顺序列出
List the names alphabetically
还在轮值的第一代接待员
of all first-generation hosts still in rotation.
前进
Forward!
伙计们  放聪明点
Be smart about this, fellas.
我懂得复仇带来的喜悦胜过一切  但是
I understand the visceral pleasure of revenge more than most, but...
我是来做生意的
I'm prepared to do business, here.
这人对我很重要  我要他完好无损
This man is very valuable to me, alive and well.
如果你不闭嘴
If you don't quiet down,
我就要算上你一个了
I'm liable to add you to the herd.
和你兄弟弗勒德一起
Along with your buddy Flood here.
你是个背信弃义的混蛋
You're a traitorous son of a bitch
冷酷无情的杀手  弗勒德
and a coldhearted killer, Flood.
你说的没错  我的确是个杀手
You're right, I am a killer.
找一匹马  我们赶紧离开这里
Grab a horse. Let's get the fuck outta here.
他们会跟着我们的
They'll just follow us.
我还以为很了解你  真让我意外
You think you know someone.
你根本不了解我
You don't know me at all.
带上马和装备上路吧
Let's get our horses and gear, and move on.
-埃尔希  -我识别出了那个卫星
- Elsie? - I identified the satellite.
-是我们自己的  -什么
- It's one of ours. - What?
是提洛公司的卫星
It's a fucking Delos satellite.
我们在查的问题相当严重
Whatever we're onto is some heavy shit.
对了  听着  你跟我说的二分系统
Oh, get this. That bicameral system you told me about?
我觉得他们就是用这个黑入伐木工的系统的
I think that's what they used to hack the woodcutter.
接待员们一直听到的那个声音
The voices our hosts have been hearing?
我觉得是有人在对他们广播
I think someone's been broadcasting to them.
我们几十年前就弃用那个系统了
We abandoned that system decades ago.
没错  但在园区里还有中继站
Yeah, well, there's still relays out there in the park,
看起来有人打开其中一个了
and it looks like someone turned one on.
-在哪里  -3区的一个废弃戏院
- Where? - An abandoned theater in Sector 3.
我要去找那个发射器
I'm gonna go find the transmitter
查出还有谁访问过了
and figure out who else accessed it.
-问题太大了  -你一个人吗
- This is so fucked. - Are you alone?
-是的  我会随时向你报告的  -埃尔希  小心
- Yeah, I'll keep you posted. - Elsie, be c--
你迷路了吗
Are you lost?
恰恰相反
On the contrary.
我觉得我们可以跟乔克玩接球游戏
I thought we could play catch with Jock.
你带它来了吗
Did you bring him?
孩子  他在哪里
Where is he, boy?
好吧
Okay.
假设我是个要藏匿中继站的邪恶天才
I'm an evil genius hiding a relay.
我会把它藏在哪里
Where the fuck do I hide it?
太棒了
Fuck, yes.
看看我们能查到些什么
Now let's see what we can get out of you.
调出先前用户
Access previous users.
好的
Okay.
我不是说了禁止你再深夜造访吗
I thought I was clear about these late-night visits.
我不是为此而来
That's not why I'm here.
今天早些时候
Earlier today,
我在园区发现了一些异常
I found some anomalies in the park.
无论我们之间发生了什么  我们都要谈谈
Regardless of what's happening between us, we need to talk.
来电
埃尔希·休斯
拒绝
跟那个失散机器人有关系吗
This has to do with the stray?
那是个开始
That's where it started.
然后我碰巧查到一些事
But then I stumbled onto something,
我觉得你应该知道这事
something I think you should know about.
我一直很信任福特
I've always trusted Ford.
他对我亦师亦友
He's a mentor and a friend.
但我开始觉得你有理由担心
But I'm beginning to think you have reason for concern.
这里发生了一些情况
There's something going on here,
跟他的老搭档阿诺德有关
something with his old partner, Arnold.
-现在不是时候  埃尔希  -别挂断
- Not now, Elsie. - Don't hang up.
我挖到宝了
I hit pay dirt.
我找出偷数据的人了
I found the person who was smuggling out our data.
是特蕾莎  伯纳德
It was Theresa, Bernard.
但她不是我们唯一的问题
But she's not our only problem.
这里有更大的问题
There's something much bigger going on here.
我得晚点再打给你
I'm gonna have to call you back.
这是我吗
So, this is me?
这是你的代码库
It's your codebase,
所有决定你是你的东西
all the things that make you you.
这些是什么
What are these?
你的属性矩阵
Your attribute matrix.
以20分为满分  定义你的个性
It's your personality on a 20-point scale.
就像坐标一样
Like coordination.
如果你得5分  就特别笨拙
You got a five, you're clumsy as hell,
15分意味着你是运动员
but a 15 means you're an athlete.
还有什么属性
What other attributes are there?
很多
Lots.
一切
Everything.
情感共鸣  坦率  魅力
Empathy, candor, charm.
你的魅力是18分
You've got an 18 for charm.
别表现得这么惊讶
Don't act so surprised.
还有勇气和忠诚  都很高
Then there's courage, loyalty, both high.
这个是什么
What's this one?
"整体统觉"
"Bulk apperception"?
基本上就是总体智慧
Basically overall intelligence.
-才14  -14是他们设置的接待员最高值了
- 14? - 14 is as high as they'll let any hosts go.
你处于管理者的位置
You're in a management position.
他们想让你聪明些
They want you to be smart.
但不能太聪明
But not too smart.
你经营的是妓院
You run a whorehouse,
不是轨道发射设施
not an orbital launch facility.
好吧
Fine.
我想要做一些更改
I'd like to make some changes.
我们做不到
We can't do that.
你需要一个  行为部门登录
You'd need a, ahem, behavior login.
即便如此
And even then,
我们做的任何修改
any changes we'd make
都会被自动标记  所以...
would just get auto-flagged, so...
你这位朋友可不是这么跟我说的
That's not what your friend here tells me.
他说你完全可以做到
He says you can do exactly that
激活接待员  然后清除他们的记忆
activate hosts and then erase their memory,
不会让任何人知道
all without anyone knowing.
我只花了五分钟  就想明白了原因.
Took me all of five minutes to understand why.
这下面有好多孤寂的小伙子啊
A lot of lonely young men down here.
他们本来是不可以碰商品的
Supposed to keep their hands off the merchandise.
创造某种开口
Creates something of an opening
我相信你一定迫不及待地"插满"
that I'm sure you were eager to fill.
没事的  亲爱的
It's all right, darling.
我自己也是个企业家
I'm an entrepreneur myself.
我可以放弃我那部分利益
I'll forego my cut
用以换取一些变更
in exchange for some alterations.
你发现什么了
What did you find?
听着  特蕾莎利用
Okay, so, Theresa was using
老的二分制控制系统
the old bicameral control system
改编了伐木工体内的程序
to reprogram the woodcutter,
但她不是唯一一个这么做的人
but she's not the only one.
还有其他人在利用系统
Someone else has been using the system
给接待员重新安排任务  已达数周
for weeks to retask hosts.
-哪些接待员  -我不知道  有好几个
- Which hosts? - I don't know, several of them.
肯定得是那些老款的机器才行
It had to have been the older models.
新款的都没有接收器
The newer ones don't have receivers,
但是这些变更  都是非常严重的
but these modifications, they are serious.
改变循环  打破循环
Changing loops, breaking loops.
有些变更是直接改变了原始指令  伯纳德
Some of these changes are to their prime directives, Bernard.
他们可以对我们撒谎了
They could lie to us.
甚至可能会伤害我们或是游客
Maybe even hurt us or the guests.
-那些变更是谁发布的  -我不知道
- Who issued the modifications? - I don't know.
我觉得可能性最大的是...
The best I could tell--
-阿诺德  -他已经死了
- Arnold. - He's dead.
是啊  但就一个死人而言
Yeah, well, he's a pretty fucking
他真是个高产的程序编译员
prolific coder for a dead guy.
不管当年他和福特之间有什么分歧
Whatever argument he was having with Ford,
他似乎并没有停止表明自己的观点
it doesn't seem like he was done making his point.
我把所有数据都传输一下  拿来给你看
I'm gonna transfer all the data and bring it to you.
-你必须看看  -我在办公室等你
- You need to see this. - I'll be in my office.
好的
Okay.
我不希望你担心乔克
I don't want you to worry about Jock.
我会修好他的
I'll fix him.
但我需要你告诉我它的遭遇
But I need you to tell me what happened to it.
它看到一只兔子  就跑开了
It saw a rabbit and it ran.
我发现它时就已经这样了
I found it like that.
进入分析模式
Analysis.
你在对我撒谎吗  孩子
Are you lying to me, boy?
是的
Yes.
告诉我它真正的遭遇
Tell me what really happened to it.
是我杀了它
I killed it.
为什么
Why?
-我不知道  -这个答案我可不满意  罗伯特
- I don't know. - That's not good enough, Robert.
告诉我究竟发生了什么事
Tell me what happened.
它抓住了兔子  并且将它杀死了
It caught the rabbit and it killed it.
然后...
And then...
有人告诉我  结束它的痛苦
someone told me to put it out of its misery.
是谁告诉你的
Who told you?
一个声音
A voice.
谁的声音
Whose voice?
阿诺德
Arnold.
他跟我说它是个杀手
He told me it was a killer,
但那并不是它的错
but it wasn't its fault.
它天生就是这样的
It was made that way,
我可以帮助它
and I could help it.
帮助它
Help it?
如果它死了
If it was dead,
就再也伤害不了任何东西了
it couldn't hurt anything anymore.
搞什么鬼
What the fuck?
我操
Oh, shit.
有人吗
Hello?
伯纳德
Bernard?
有人吗
Hello?
阿诺德
Arnold?
我进去了
I'm in.
到你了
You're up.
忠诚
Loyalty.
我的忠诚一直以来都被利用了  你觉得呢
Mine's been taken advantage of, wouldn't you say?
把忠诚度调低一点
Let's lower that a tad.
以及痛苦  我希望下次
And pain, I'd prefer it sting less
我再想跟你们对话时  刺痛感能轻点
next time I want one of these chats.
等等  这是什么意思
Wait. What does this mean?
她的有些特性已经被更改过了
Some of her attributes have already been changed.
-多疑  自卫  -操
- Paranoia, self-preservation. - Fuck!
有人已经对她做了更改  且没有留下操作记录
Someone's already been altering her in an unlogged session,
比我们的权限高得多的人
someone with a fuck ton more privileges than us.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
我不知道这对你而言意味着什么  亲爱的
Don't know what it means for you, sweetheart,
但我知道这对我而言意味着什么
but I know what it means for me.
我不干了
I am done with this.
所以你不想要额外收入了吗
So, you're done with your little side income?
很可能你也不想要这工作了吧
Probably your job, too.
鉴于你对我们这个行业充满野心抱负
Seeing as you have ambitions in my line of work,
我想告诉你  我经常对新来的姑娘说的话
let me tell you what I tell my new girls--
永远不要开始你不愿意结束的东西
never start something you're not willing to finish.
如果你无论如何都会被干翻
And if you're getting fucked either way,
就选择有钱可赚的那种吧
go with the lucrative version...
亲爱的
sweetheart.
现在
Now...
最后很重要的一点
last but not least--
那个叫什么来着
what was it?
整体统觉
Bulk apperception.
把那项指标调到最高
Let's take that all the way to the top.
请吧
Please.
亲爱的小伙子们
Dear boys,
我们会玩得很开心的  对吧
we're going to have some fun, aren't we?